



Sergey Kovalev

Frontend developer

(+375297068180



sk85post@gmail.com



Minsk, Belarus

PROFESSIONAL SUMMARY

I'm a Frontend Developer with 1.5+ years of experience specializing in application development using React.js, Next.js, TypeScript, JavaScript, Redux, Redux-toolkit, Tailwind, Vite. Familar with unit testing using Jest/Vitest and React Testing Library. Have experience in selecting project architecture and technology stack, took a part in a team work of 3 developers. Adheres to best coding standards and code review practices, including SOLID, DRY, KISS, YAGNI, and design patterns.

EXPERIENCE

September 2024 - October 2024

Frontend Developer

T1 Group / Belarus, Minsk

Proffesional education - Advanced training course in frontend development:

- · browser operation, critical rendering path, optimization
- patterns, architecture, microservices
- state managers
- · client-server interaction
- · testing
- · algorithms and data structures
- advanced react (fiber, ssr, ssg)

Developed SPA with authorisation, catalog of products, cart, detail information about product.

Technologies: TypeScript, React, Redux-toolkit, RTK-query, Eslint, Prettier, Vite.

- Deployment of the final product in github: https://github.com/sk85web/goods4you/
- Deploy of the final product on gh-pages: https://sk85web.github.io/goods4you/

October 2023 - June 2024

Proffesional education - Developed a book e-commerce website using TypeScript, React and Redux:

- Layout design in Figma (HTML & CSS).
- Implementation of user authentication system (Redux-saga)
- · Creation of forms for seamless user interaction
- · Dynamic search functionality with server requests
- Deployment of the final product in github: https://github.com/sk85web/book-store
- Deploy on Netlify: https://sk85-book-store.netlify.app
- September 2023 May 2024

Frontend Developer

The Rolling Scopes School / Belarus, Minsk

Professional education - Developed multiple applications during coursework:

- Created several applications starting from vanilla JavaScript to Single Page Applications (SPA) using TypeScript, Webpack, modular programming, and fetch requests.
- Final project: an e-commerce application as part of a team using Tailwind CSS, TypeScript, React, Redux Toolkit, and Vite.

EDUCATION

September 2003 - May 2008

Graduate

Belarusian National Technical University / Belarus, Minsk

• October 2023 - June 2024

Graduate

Programming school TeachMeSkills / Belarus, Minsk

September 2023 - May 2024

Graduate

The Rolling Scopes School / Belarus, Minsk

LANGUAGES

English

Russian

TECHNOLOGY SUMMARY

Languages: JavaScript, TypeScript

Frameworks and Libraries: React.js, Redux, Redux Toolkit, Next.js

 $\textbf{Development Tools:} \ Jest, Vitest, ESLint, Prettier, Webpack, Git$

Methodologies: SOLID, DRY, KISS, YAGNI, Design Patterns

Additional Skills: Tailwind, Vite, REST API, Figma, GitHub